//QUESTION DATA
const QUESTIONS = [
    {
        question:'How many bones are in the adult human body?',
        answers: [ 
            '500', 
            '206', 
            '107',
            '300',
            ],
        correctAnswer: '206',
        explanation: 'There are 206 bones in the adult human body. I newborn baby will have 300, but many fuse during development.'
    },
    {
        question:'What is the primary function of muscles?',
        answers: [
            'Movement', 
            'Heat Production', 
            'Stability', 
            'All of the above' 
            ],
        correctAnswer: 'All of the above',
        explanation: 'The muscular system carries out all of these functions. Each one is vital to survival.'
    },
    {
        question:'What part of the brain is responsible for providing feedback on the position of the body in order to coordinate movement?',
        answers: [
            'Cerebrum', 
            'Midbrain', 
            'Cerebellum', 
            'The Limbic System' 
            ],
        correctAnswer: 'Cerebellum',
        explanation: 'The Cerebellum compares indended movement patterns with actual movement patterns in order to carry out better future patterns. It is responsible to awareness of where your body is in space.'
    },
    {
        question:'Which vertebrae have the largest vertebral bodies?',
        answers: [
            'Cervical', 
            'Thoracic', 
            'Lumbar', 
            'Sacral' 
            ],
        correctAnswer: 'Lumbar',
        explanation: 'The lumbar vertebrae have the largest bodies because they are responsible for supporting the majority of your body\'s weight'
    },
    {
        question:'Which muscle/s is/are responsible for closing the jaw?',
        answers: [
            'Masseter and Temporalis', 
            'Pterygoids', 
            'Trapezius and Sternocleidomastoid', 
            'Deltiods' 
            ],
        correctAnswer: 'Masseter and Temporalis',
        explanation: 'These two muscles are the primary elevators of the mandible. The pterygoids are responsible for lateral jaw translation while the others aid in neck, back and shoulder movement.'
    },
    {
        question:'Which direction do arteries carry blood?',
        answers: [
            'Toward the heart', 
            'Away from the bones', 
            'Away from the heart', 
            'To the brain only' 
            ],
        correctAnswer: 'Away from the heart',
        explanation: 'Arteries are responsible for carrying blood away from the heart while veins are responsible for carrying blood to the heart.'
    },
    {
        question:'Which of the following is the thinnest blood vessel?',
        answers: [
            'Veins', 
            'Arterioles', 
            'Meta Arterioles', 
            'Capillaries' 
            ],
        correctAnswer: 'Capillaries',
        explanation: 'Capillaries contain a single cell barrier and are the site of nutrient and gas exchange between the blood and the body.'
    },
    {
        question:'Which type of joint lies at the shoulder joint and hip joint',
        answers: [
            'Pivot joint', 
            'Ball and Socket joint', 
            'Rotation joint', 
            'Hinge joint' 
            ],
        correctAnswer: 'Ball and Socket joint',
        explanation: 'Ball and socket joints have a round head that fits into a shallow depression. They are able to move freely in any direction.'
    },
    {
        question:'An electrocardiogram is a graphic illustration of?',
        answers: [
            'Cardiac conduction system', 
            'Respiratory cycle', 
            'Cardiac output', 
            'Cardiac cycle' 
            ],
        correctAnswer: 'Cardiac conduction system',
        explanation: 'Electrocardiograms measure the electrical activity of the heart.'
    },
    {
        question:'The brain and spinal cord together make up?',
        answers: [
            'Central nervous system', 
            'Main nervous system', 
            'Peripheral nervous sustem', 
            'Nerons' 
            ],
        correctAnswer: 'Central nervous system',
        explanation: 'The central nervous system consists of the brain and spinal chord.'
    }
];